Guide to the Indochinese postcards, [ca. 1902-1994]
Indochinese postcards, [ca. 1902-1994]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Indochinese postcards, [ca. 1902-1994]
4279
.1 cubic ft.
Postcards.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Postcards, some with messages, some sent to individuals in France, depicting landscapes, street scenes, activities, ethnic groups, and events, primarily in the Vietnamese sections of Cochin China, Annam, and Tonkin. Includes some postcards from Cambodia and Laos and two sets of postcards from North Vietnam (post 1954). Also 44 postcards of Buddhist temples in Vietnam, 1990s, by David D. Ha (Pacific Distributor).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Postcards, some with messages, some sent to individuals in France, depicting landscapes, street scenes, activities, ethnic groups, and events, primarily in the Vietnamese sections of Cochin China, Annam, and Tonkin. Includes some postcards from Cambodia and Laos and two sets of postcards from North Vietnam (post 1954). Also 44 postcards of Buddhist temples in Vietnam, 1990s, by David D. Ha (Pacific Distributor).
SUBJECTS
Places:
Indochina--Description--Views.; Vietnam--Description--Views.; Cambodia--Description--Views.; Laos--Description--Views.
Form and Genre Terms:
Postcards.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Cochin China
  - Saigon, Cholon - scenes, street scenes, activities, ethnic groups - blank (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Saigon - street scenes, activities - Goupil Family, ca. 1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Saigon, Cholon - theater scenes - Goupil family (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chaudoc, Thu-Doc - scenes, street scenes - Goupil family, ca. 1909 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Saigon, Cholon - scenes - Larue family, ca. 1906 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Saigon, Cholon - scenes, mostly in color - from "Alexander", 1908 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Saigon, Cholon - street scenes, scenes, people - various senders and recipients, 1907-1913 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Tonkin
  - Hanoi, Haiphong - scenes, street scenes, activities - various senders and recipients, ca. 1905-1920 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Moncay, Caobang, Kien An, Phong-Tho, Thai-Nguyen, Doson - scenes, ethnic groups - various senders and recipients, ca. 1905-1913 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hanoi, Haiphong, etc. - scenes, street scenes - Larue family, 1902-1904 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - People - blank (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - People - blank (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hanoi, Doson, Moncay, Laokay - activities - blank (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Execution scenes - blank, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Animals - blank (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sontay, Ngnan-Son, Phu-Lien, Vie'tri, Nui-Deo, Cho-Bo, Tong-Hoa-Phu - scenes - blank (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Doson, Hongay, Nam-Dinh, Moncay, Nacham, Muong-Khuong - scenes - blank (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hanoi, Nam Dinh, etc. - street scenes (2 in color) - blank (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Missionary activities (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Yunnam - Larue family - blank (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Annam
  - Hue (2 in color) - Larue family - blank (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hue - blank (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Than-Hoa, Man-Hoa, Qui-Nhon - blank (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - People - addressed and blank (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Vinh - blank (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Tourane - addressed and blank, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Cambodia
  - People - blank (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Pnom-Penh - coronation, cremation ceremony, scenes, street scenes - Larue family and others, 1903-1913 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - People - blank (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Scenes - Larue family, from "Alexander", 1903, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ethnic groups - Larue family, others - blank, ca. 1903 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- North Vietnam (post-1954)
  - Halong and environs - blank in folder (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Hanoi - incomplete set, blank in folder (Box 1, Folder 33)